Julian E. Levi
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Financial Records, 1920s-1980, Series 5:; (Box 3; 0.4 linear ft.)
  - Art Sales, Commissions, Consignments; Gallery Expenses; Art Received/Returned (Box 3)
    - Alan Gallery, 1953-1958 (Box 3)
    - Associated American Artists, 1940-1972, undated (Box 3)
    - Downtown Gallery, 1936-1958, undated (Box 3)
    - Nordness Gallery (Box 3)
    - Rehn Gallery (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Galleries (A-Z, unidentified), 1960-1980, undated (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Commissions, 1928-1964, undated (Box 3)
  - Amalgamated Bank of New York, 1941 (Box 3)
  - First National City Bank, 1938-1972 (Box 3)
  - Estate of Rosa Gomprecht (J. Levi a beneficiary), 1938-1939 (Box 3)
  - Julian E. and Jean L. Levi Investments, 1942-1975 (Box 3)
  - Elsie Levi [sister] Investments, 1958-1964 (Box 3)
  - Loan, undated (Box 3)
  - Pay Stubs (teaching, lecturing, writing), 1940-1972, undated (Box 3)
  - Real Estate Records, 1926-1970, undated (Box 3)
  - Receipts and Invoices (Box 3)
    - Antique Collection (purchases and sales), 1938-1975, undated (Box 3)
    - Art Supplies, 1927-1963, undated (Box 3)
    - Business Expenses, Miscellaneous, 192[?], 1941-1981, undated (Box 3)
    - Contributions, 1940-1966 (Box 3)
    - Framing, 1940-1977 (Box 3)
    - Household, Construction and Repairs, 1947-1972, undated (Box 3)
    - Household, General, 1934-1974, undated (Box 3)
    - Insurance, 1942-1972, undated (Box 3)
    - Personal Expenses, 1927-1981, undated (Box 3)
    - Photography, 1940-1970, undated (Box 3)
    - Shipping, 1940-1973 (Box 3)
    - Travel, 1920s-1968, undated (Box 3)
    - Royalty Statements, 1950-1980, undated (Box 3)
  - Taxes (Box 3)
    - Local Property Tax (East Hampton, N.Y.), 1956-1971 (Box 3)
    - Federal Income Tax (returns and related items), 1945-1969 (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks, 1921-1940, Series 6:; (Box 4; 2 folders)
  Two disbound volumes contain printed material such as clippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements that document Levi's career. Vol. 1, in addition to printed material, contains 4 photographs of artwork by Levi and one strip of 3 contact prints of large groups of people that include Levi.
  - Vol. 1, 2, 1921-1940 (Box 4)
- Printed Material, 1897-1981, Series 7:; (Boxes 4-6, OV 10; 2.2 linear ft.)
  This series is arranged into 4 subseries:
  7.1: Printed Material By Levi, 1922, circa 1961
  7.2: Printed Material About/Mentioning Levi, circa 1934-1980
  7.3: Exhibition Printed Material, circa 1930-1981
  7.4: Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1897-1981
  - Printed Material By Levi, 1922, circa 1961, 7.1:
    - Article, "Clive Bell and the Artistic Problem" in Gargoyle, June, 1922 (Box 4)
    - Book, Modern Art: An Introduction, circa 1961 (Box 4)
  - Printed Material About/Mentioning Levi, circa 1934-1980, 7.2:
    - Book Prospectuses and Advertisements, 1945-1961, undated (Box 4)
    - Clippings About/Mentioning Levi or containing Reproductions of his Work, 1934-1980, undated, (6 folders) (Box 4)
    - Events and Programs (Levi an honoree or sponsor), 1942-1969, undated (Box 4)
    - Fundraising Auctions and Raffles (Levi a contributor), 1942-1953, undated (Box 4)
    - Lecture Notices, undated (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Items, 1942-1968, undated (Box 4)
    - Press Releases, 1941-1964, undated (Box 4)
    - Reproductions of Work by Levi, undated (Box 4)
    - Teaching (school catalogs, course descriptions, etc.), 1949-1968 (Box 4)
  - Exhibitions, 1930-1981, undated, 7.3:
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations, 1930-1965, (11 folders) (Box 4)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations, 1966-1976, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Prospectuses (Levi on Jury or Committee), 1947-1977, undated (Box 5)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations (Other Artists), 1934-1981, undated, (8 folders) (Box 5)
    - Exhibition Posters and Announcements (Other Artists; see: OV 10), 1951-1975, undated (Box 5)
    - Exhibition Prospectuses, circa 1935-1962, undated (Box 5)
    - Student Exhibition Catalogs (New School for Social Research), 1963-1977 (Box 5)
    - Oversized Exhibition Posters and Announcements (Other Artists), 1951-1975, undated (Box OV 10)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1897-1981, undated, 7.4:
    - Auction Catalogs, 1941-1943 (Box 5)
    - Book Prospectuses, undated (Box 5)
    - Books (The Oasis by Mary McCarthy; Poems by the Peninsula Poets), 1949, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Brochures about Art Services, Galleries, etc., 1972, undated (Box 5)
    - Brochures about Art Supplies, undated (Box 5)
    - Clippings (Box 5)
      - Art Related (not mentioning Levi), 1930-1981, undated, (8 folders) (Box 5)
      - Baseball, 1959-1969, undated (Box 5)
      - Birds, 1972, undated (Box 5)
      - Dogs, 1941-1962, undated (Box 5)
      - Football, 1959-1979 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous Topics, 1937-1981, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Illustrations, 1897-1900, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Investment Information, 1949-1976, undated (Box 5)
    - Invitations, 1917-1981, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Items (Box 6)
      - Art Related, circa 1938-1951, undated (Box 6)
      - Not Art Related, 1956-1979, undated (Box 6)
    - Newsletters and Other Periodicals, 1939-1981 (Box 6)
    - Conference, Lecture and Meeting Notices, circa 1940-1949, undated (Box 6)
    - Political Leaflets and Related Items, circa 1932-1971 (Box 6)
    - Blank Post Cards, undated (Box 6)
    - Programs (play, concert), 1945-1954, undated (Box 6)
    - Publications (not exhibition catalogs) (Box 6)
      - Art Organizations, 1971-1979, undated (Box 6)
      - Museums, 1920-1981, undated (Box 6)
      - Other Organizations, 1964-1974 (Box 6)
    - Reproductions of Art by Other Artists, undated (Box 6)
    - Travel Brochures and Printed Souvenirs, 1926-1967, undated (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous Records, circa 1936-1974, Series 8:; (Box 6, OV 9; 0.2 linear ft.)
  Of particular interest are items pertaining to the American Artists' Congress, An American Group, Inc., Downtown Gallery, and New York City Council for Art Week. Other items of note are a blueprint of plans for Levi's studio at his home in Easthampton, New York, records regarding the New School for Social Research where Levi taught for many years.
  - American Artists' Congress (Outline of Program held at the New School; Agenda for Exhibition Committee Meeting), 1936, 1940 (Box 6)
  - An American Group, Inc. (Box 6)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, 1941 (Box 6)
    - Membership Lists, 1942, undated (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Records and Fragments, 1941, undated (Box 6)
    - Notes of Meeting, March 29, undated (Box 6)
    - Raffle Winners (lists and ticket stubs), undated (Box 6)
  - Copper Etching Plate (Winnie the Pooh illustration) and Half-Tone Printing Plate (portrait of Julian Levi), undated (Box 6)
  - Downtown Gallery (Box 6)
    - Artists' Statements, undated (Box 6)
    - Minutes of Artists' Meetings, 1946-1953 (Box 6)
    - Minutes of Board of Directors, Edith Halpert Foundation, Inc. (Julian Levi on Board), 1950-1964 (Box 6)
  - Guestbook from Julian Levi Exhibition at Rehn Gallery, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Joint Artists-Museums Committee, 1955 (Box 6)
  - New School for Social Research, 1954-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - New York City Council for Art Week - Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Postage Stamp honoring Stuart Davis, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Stationery Samples, undated (Box 6)
  - Survey of the Economic Position of the Graphic Arts (tentative memorandum and proposal), 1940 (Box 6)
  - Blueprint of Plans for Levi's Studio in East Hampton, N.Y. (Herman Neumann, architect), 1956 (Box OV 9)
- Photographs, circa 1902-1974, Series 9:; (Boxes 6-8, OV 11; 1.1 linear ft)
  Photographs of artwork include a disbound album of Levi's work and exhibition installation views that show paintings by Levi. The collection contains pictures of Levi at various ages, including some taken when he was a child. Will Barnet, Isabel Bishop, Louis Bouché, Byron Browne, Edwin Dickinson, Frank DuMond, Robert Hale, Chris and John Hovannes, Morris Kantor, Norman Kent, Stewart Klonis, Yasuo Kuniyoshi, Jack Levine, Reginald Marsh, Kenneth H. Miller, Walter Pach, and William Zorach are among the individuals identified in group pictures.
  Many photographs of places (specifically beach scenes and seascapes) probably were used as reference for paintings. Photographs of other places of interest include Downtown Gallery, Stuart Davis's grave, and studios he occupied while in Paris, circa 1926-1927 and at the American Academy in Rome, 1967-1968. Pictures of the interior and exterior of Levi's home in Easthampton, New York, show some of his antique collection as well as his studio.
  Miscellaneous subjects consist mainly of pets. Of particular note are copies of Resettlement Administration and Farm Security Administration photographs. Levi may have acquired these while employed in the W. P. A. Federal Art Project.
  Additional photographs of works of art and people enclosed with letters, and original photographs that serve as Christmas cards, are filed with Correspondence. Also, there are a small number of photographs in Vol. 1 of the Scrapbooks.
  This series is arranged into 5 subseries:
  9.1: Artwork, circa 1926-1965
  9.2: People, circa 1902-1974
  9.3: Places, 1926-1969
  9.4: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1930s-1940s
  9.5: Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, 1961-1971, undated
  - Artwork, 1926-1965, undated, 9.1:
    - Artwork by Levi (Box 6)
      - Album of Paintings by Levi (disbound), 1926-1945 (Box 6)
      - Exhibition Installation, Art Students' League, undated (Box 6)
      - Exhibition Installation, Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1960 (Box 6)
      - Exhibition Installations, Carnegie Institute, 1941-1948 (Box 6)
      - Exhibition Installation, Rehn Gallery, undated (Box 6)
      - Exhibition Installation, Unidentified Parisian Restaurant and Bar, circa 1926-1927 (Box 6)
      - Exhibition Installations, Unidentified, undated (Box 6)
      - Paintings, 1939-1965, undated (Box 6)
      - Paintings (duplicates), undated (Box 6)
    - By Other Artists, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6)
  - People, circa 1902-1974, undated, 9.2:
    - Levi (Box 6)
      - Julian E. (as a boy; siblings included in all but one view), circa 1902-circa 1910 (Box 6)
      - Julian E. (as a young and middle aged man; see also OV 11), circa 1920s-1950s (Box 6)
      - Julian E. (as an older man), circa 1960s-1970s (Box 6)
      - Julian E. in his Studio, 1920s-1966, undated (Box 6)
      - Julian E. with Dogs, undated (Box 6)
      - Julian E. with Groups (see also OV 11), 1920s - circa 1970, undated (Box 6)
      - Julian E. with Others (Louis Bouché, Yasuo Kiniyoski, Jack Levine, Norman Kent, and unidentified), 1954-1969, undated (Box 6)
      - Julian E. with Students, 1973, undated (Box 6)
      - Julian E. and Beatrice Graitcer (first wife), circa 1930-1935 (Box 6)
      - Julian E. and Jean Laurent (wife), 1952, undated (Box 6)
      - Jean Laurent, 1952, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7 (hol))
    - Family, Friends, and Colleagues (includes one of Yasuo Kuniyoshi), circa 1919, 1956-1974, undated, (5 folders) (Box 7 (hol))
    - Julian E. Levi (as a young and middle aged man), circa 1920s–1950s (Box OV 11)
    - Julian E. Levi with Groups, undated (Box OV 11)
  - Places, circa 1926-1969, 9.3:
    - Beaches, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Beaches and Piers with Boats, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Buildings, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Cityscapes, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Diablo Dam, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Downtown Gallery (exterior, with sigh announcing Levi's one-man show), 1940s (Box 7 (hol))
    - Grave of Stuart Davis in Green River Cemetery, Long Island, 1964 (Box 7 (hol))
    - Landscapes, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Landscapes with Buildings, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Levi's Home, East Hampton, N.Y., 1947-1969, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7 (hol))
    - Seascapes, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Studios occupied by Levi (Box 7 (hol))
      - American Academy in Rome, 1967-1968 (Box 7 (hol))
      - Paris (rue de Moulon-Vert, leased from William Hayter), 1926-1927 (Box 7 (hol))
    - Miscellaneous Views, undated (Box 7 (hol))
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1930s-1940s, 9.4:
    - Cats and Dogs, undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Dog (Vicki), undated (Box 7 (hol))
    - Resettlement Administration and Farm Security Administration, 1930s-1940s (Box 7 (hol))
  - Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies,circa 1961-1971, 9.5:
    - Color Slides (Box 8 (pam))
      - Artwork (by Levi), 1961-1971, undated (Box 8 (pam))
      - People (Levi, Julian E. and with Others, including students), 1964, undated (Box 8 (pam))
    - Color Transparency, Artwork, undated (Box 8 (pam))
    - Negatives (Box 8 (pam))
      - Artwork, undated (Box 8 (pam))
      - People, undated (Box 8 (pam))
      - Places (buildings, Downtown Gallery exterior, cityscapes, landscapes, Levi Home in East Hampton, and seascapes), undated (Box 8 (pam))
      - Miscellaneous Subjects, undated (Box 8 (pam))